## Marija Popeska

## **UX Engineer**

E-mail

marija.popeska@gmail.com

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/popeskamarija/

Github

https://github.com/marijapopeska

Dribbble

https://dribbble.com/marijapopeska

Master of Architecture and designing, after 4 years of experience I transitioned from Architect to UX Designer and was completely self-directed because I found many similarities Architects strive to design functional and aesthetically pleasing spaces in ways that make their users happy and encourage them to keep coming back. Sound familiar to UX? The way I see it — the only difference between architecture and UX design is the medium; - Architecture deals with physical environments and -UX deals with digital environments. I found out that my architectural background is an excellent asset, that provides me with plenty of transferable skills, plus the advantage of bringing a different perspective into the field of UX Designing.

## Work experience

05/2018 – 10/2018 **UX/UI Designer, Internship** 

Artistika Creative Digital Agency UI/UX

2018 — 2021 **Architect** 

Civil Engineering Institut of Macedonia

2021 - 2022 **Architect** 

Taktik Architecture

2022 — 2023 **UX/UI Designer** 

Hoyo Tech

## **Education**

2014-2020 Faculty of Architecture - Master of Architecture

ss. Cyril and Methodius University, Skopje,

North Macedonia

**Courses** 

12/10/2023 Udemy Course - Certificate

Figma UI/UX Design Advanced

12/25/2023 Udemy Course - Certificate

Web and Mobile Designer

Skills	Tools	Web development
User Interface	Figma	HTML
User Experience	Adobe Photoshop	CSS
Web Design	Adobe Ilustrator	Tailwind CSS
Frontend development	3dsMax	React
		Next.js